<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Peaky Blinders Characters</string>

    <string name="c1">Character 1</string>
    <string name="c2">Character 2</string>
    <string name="c3">Character 3</string>
    <string name="c4">Character 4</string>
    <string name="c5">Character 5</string>
    <string name="c6">Character 6</string>
    <string name="c7">Character 7</string>
    <string name="c8">Character 8</string>
    <string name="c9">Character 9</string>
    <string name="c10">Character 10</string>
    <string name="c11">Character 11</string>
    <string name="c12">Character 12</string>
    <string name="c13">Character 13</string>
    <string name="c14">Character 14</string>
    <string name="c15">Character 15</string>
    <string name="c16">Character 16</string>
    <string name="c17">Character 17</string>
    <string name="c18">Character 18</string>
    <string name="c19">Character 19</string>
    <string name="c20">Character 20</string>
    <string name="c21">Character 21</string>
    <string name="c22">Character 22</string>
    <string name="c23">Character 23</string>
    <string name="c24">Character 24</string>
    <string name="c25">Character 25</string>
    <string name="c26">Character 26</string>
    <string name="c27">Character 27</string>
    <string name="c28">Character 28</string>
    <string name="c29">Character 29</string>
    <string name="c30">Character 30</string>



    <string name="aberama">Aberama Gold</string>
    <string name="abremades">A fierce Romani Gypsy and skilled fighter, Aberama Gold becomes an ally of the Shelby family. His loyalty is unwavering, and his past as a carnival strongman adds to his enigmatic and imposing presence.</string>


    <string name="ada">Ada Thorne</string>
    <string name="adades"> The only sister of the Shelby siblings, Ada starts as a rebellious member of the family but eventually distances herself from the criminal activities. Her compassion and desire for a different life lead her to love and marriage with Freddie Thorne, a former communist.</string>


    <string name="alfie">Alfie Solomons</string>
    <string name="alfiedes">A cunning Jewish gangster, Alfie Solomons operates in Camden Town. His eccentricity is matched only by his intelligence and ruthlessness. A shrewd negotiator and a master of manipulation, he forms an uneasy alliance with the Shelby family.</string>

    <string name="arthur">Arthur Shelby</string>
    <string name="arthurdes">The elder brother of the Shelby siblings, Arthur is a charismatic yet tormented figure. His violent tendencies are both a strength and a weakness, as he struggles with his role in the criminal world and his desire for a better life.</string>

    <string name="ben">Ben Younger</string>
    <string name="bendes">Ben Younger was a colonel and head of army intelligence officers who arrived in Birmingham and arrested Ada Shelby over her communist past.</string>

    <string name="billikimber">Billy Kimber</string>
    <string name="billydes">A formidable antagonist in the early seasons, Billy Kimber is a ruthless and ambitious gang leader. His control over Birmingham\'s criminal underworld creates a direct conflict with the Shelby family\'s rise to power.</string>


    <string name="changretta">Luca Changretta</string>
    <string name="changrettades">A cunning Italian gangster, Luca Changretta seeks vengeance against the Shelby family for personal reasons. His meticulous planning and strategic mind make him a formidable adversary. His vendetta drives a significant plot arc, showcasing his determination and willingness to go to extreme lengths to achieve his goals.</string>

    <string name="charlie">Charlie</string>
    <string name="charliedes">A loyal and respected member of the Shelby family\'s inner circle, Charlie Strong is their blacksmith and an essential part of their operations. He\'s known for his strong work ethic, trustworthiness, and commitment to the Peaky Blinders.</string>

    <string name="curly">Curly</string>
    <string name="curlydes">A member of the Peaky Blinders gang, Curly is often seen as a comedic figure within the group. Despite his jovial nature, he plays a supporting role in various activities and adds a lighter touch to the intense world of the Shelby family. </string>

    <string name="duke">Duke Shelby</string>
    <string name="dukedes">Duke is a young member of the Shelby family, belonging to the generation after the main characters. While not extensively explored in the show, he represents the ongoing legacy of the Shelby clan.</string>

    <string name="esma">Esme Shelby</string>
    <string name="esmedes">Esme is the former wife of John Shelby and a prominent member of the Shelby family. With a Romani background, her fierce loyalty and strong-willed nature make her a key figure within the family dynamics. Her struggles with tragedy and loyalty reflect the challenges faced by the Shelby clan, and her character adds depth to the show\'s exploration of love and sacrifice.</string>

    <string name="finn">Finn Shelby</string>
    <string name="finndes">The youngest of the Shelby siblings, Finn starts as a naive and impressionable teenager. As the series progresses, he grows into a more capable and involved member of the family business. </string>

    <string name="freddie">Freddie Thorne</string>
    <string name="freddiedes">Freddie is Ada Shelby\'s husband and a former communist activist. His relationship with Ada sparks tensions within the Shelby family due to their differing backgrounds. A principled man, Freddie\'s involvement in political movements clashes with the Shelby\'s criminal enterprises.</string>

    <string name="gina">Gina Grey</string>
    <string name="ginades">Gina is the wife of Michael Gray, a member of the Shelby family. She brings an outsider\'s perspective to the family dynamics, having come from a wealthy American family. Her marriage to Michael and her eventual involvement in the Shelby operations lead to both personal and professional challenges.</string>

    <string name="grace">Grace Shelby</string>
    <string name="gracedes">Grace is a significant character in the early seasons of Peaky Blinders. Initially an undercover agent for the Birmingham police, she becomes entangled with Thomas Shelby and eventually falls in love with him.</string>

    <string name="jack">Jack Nelson</string>
    <string name="jackdes">Jack Nelson is a major antagonist in Peaky Blinders, serving as an unseen antagonist in Season 5 and one of the two secondary antagonists (alongside Diana Mitford) of Season 6. He is an Irish-American gangster with ties to high-level politicians, such as President Roosevelt.</string>

    <string name="jeremaiah">Jeremaiah</string>
    <string name="jeremiahdes">He is a powerful and respected member of the Birmingham-based Sabini gang, a rival gang to the Peaky Blinders. Jeremiah Jesus has a strong presence in London\'s criminal underworld and is known for his enigmatic and calculated personality.</string>

    <string name="jessie">Jessie Eden</string>
    <string name="jessiedes">Jessie Eden is a historical character based on a real-life figure. In Peaky Blinders, she is portrayed as a union organizer and political activist who becomes involved with the workers\' movement in Birmingham. </string>

    <string name="john">John Shelby</string>
    <string name="johndes">The second eldest Shelby sibling, John, is a key enforcer for the family. His tough exterior hides a more sensitive side, often struggling with the violent nature of their operations.</string>

    <string name="johnnydogs">Johnny Dogs</string>
    <string name="johnnydes">A Romani Gypsy and loyal ally of the Shelby family, Johnny Dogs contributes his unique skills and insights to their operations. As a trusted confidant, his knowledge of the Romani traditions and connections within the community make him an important figure, adding depth to the show\'s exploration of cultural dynamics and alliances.</string>

    <string name="linda">Linda Shelby</string>
    <string name="lindades">Linda is Arthur Shelby\'s wife, who comes from a more conventional background. Her efforts to reconcile her marriage with Arthur\'s violent lifestyle reflect the challenges of the Shelby family\'s criminal endeavors. Linda\'s presence introduces a contrasting perspective and adds complexity to Arthur\'s character, as he grapples with his loyalty to both family and spouse.</string>

    <string name="lizzie">Lizzie Shelby</string>
    <string name="lizziedes">A trusted member of the Shelby family. Her relationship with Tommy Shelby evolves from a business arrangement to a deeper connection. Lizzie\'s journey reflects themes of empowerment, as she navigates the criminal world and asserts her own agency, making her a resilient and integral character in the Peaky Blinders series.</string>

    <string name="campbell">Major Campbell</string>
    <string name="campbelldes">nspector Campbell is a Belfast-born detective sent to Birmingham to suppress the Peaky Blinders. His dogged determination and ruthless tactics make him a formidable adversary to the Shelby family. </string>

    <string name="micheal">Micheal Grey</string>
    <string name="michealDes">Introduced as Polly\'s biological son from a previous relationship, Michael becomes integrated into the Shelby family. His intelligence and strategic thinking make him a valuable asset, leading to his involvement in the family\' business. Michael\'s journey showcases his growth from an outsider to a central figure within the Shelby clan, while also highlighting the challenges of straddling the line between legitimacy and criminality.</string>

    <string name="mosley">Oswald Mosley</string>
    <string name="mosleydes">Oswald Mosley is a historical figure depicted in Peaky Blinders as a British politician and fascist leader. His charm and charisma attract followers as he advocates for extreme ideologies. Mosley\'s interactions with the Shelby family, particularly with Tommy, create a tense dynamic that reflects the political and social turmoil of the time.</string>


    <string name="polly">Polly Grey</string>
    <string name="pollydes">The matriarch of the Shelby family, Polly is a strong-willed and complex character. Her past as a former gypsy and her involvement in criminal activities give her a unique perspective. Polly\'s maternal instincts and business acumen make her an essential figure in the Shelby operations, while her personal struggles and relationships contribute to the emotional depth of the show.</string>

    <string name="ruby">Ruby Shelby</string>
    <string name="rubydes">Ruby Shelby was the daughter of Thomas and Lizzie Shelby and half-sister of Charles Shelby. She was named by her paternal great-aunt, Polly Gray.</string>

    <string name="tattiana">Tatiana Petrovna</string>
    <string name="tattianades">Tatiana is a character introduced in Peaky Blinders as a Russian aristocrat who fled the Russian Revolution. Her interactions with Thomas Shelby involve both personal and political matters. As an outsider to British society, Tatiana\'s presence brings an international dimension to the show\'s world, while her connections and motives create intrigue and complications within the story.</string>

    <string name="thomas">Thomas Shelby</string>
    <string name="thomasdes">The central character of Peaky Blinders, Thomas Shelby is the cunning and ambitious leader of the Shelby family. His strategic mind, charisma, and determination drive the family\'s rise in the criminal world. Thomas\'s complexities are showcased through his struggles with PTSD, his relationships, and his constant battles for power and control. His journey forms the core of the show, depicting his evolution from a war veteran to a formidable figure in Birmingham\'s underworld.</string>


    <string name="tomasson">Charles Shelby</string>
    <string name="thomassondes">Charles Thomas Burgess Shelby was born in 1922, Birmingham, to Thomas and Grace Shelby.</string>
</resources>